Dominic J Mitchell

Front End Web Designer & Developer Providence, RI Area

dominic.joseph.mitchell.2018@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u> **DJMPortfolio**

Full Stack developer, specializing in front & back end web design. Business professional who has the drive to succeed, with 8 years in technology and experience in management, leadership, and construction. Why I enjoy tech: The drive to succeed, the passion for learning, development of new skills, and the knowledge gained.

Technical Skills

Front end: Back end:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Agile, React, Ajax, jQuery, wire-frames, SASS, VS Code, Scrum/Agile, Git-Hub, Bash, Git, Handlebars Visual Studio, MVC & SQL, Angular AWS, Ruby on Rails, SQL, RESTful API, Heroku, JSON, Express, Node.js, ASP.NET MVC PostgreSQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, Razor, C#

Web Development Projects https://dominicjosephmitchell.github.io/DJMPortfolio/

Trails: Welcome to Southern New England Trails, create an index of the trails that you have experienced.

(HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, and Express-Node.js)

Bucket List: Integrate with a third-party location-based API to allow to search for a location/venue to add to their bucket

list. (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Leaflet(map), Ajax, MongoDB, Mongoose and Express – Node.js)

Tic Tac Toe: A front-end JavaScript game engine using a third-party API. (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Flex-box, JavaScript)

Vacations: Multi-page user experience designed photo album. (HTML, CSS)

Family Tree: Ancestry database. Build your family tree. (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)

Education

GA – General Assembly Providence RI Software Engineering Immersive

Twelve week web development immersive program (600hrs plus)

Institute – of – Entrepreneurial & Leadership Providence RI Web Design & Development

HTML - CSS - JavaScript

New Horizons Computer Learning Center Providence RI Network Support Technician

CompTIA: A+, Network+, Security+ Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)

Microsoft Certified Desktop Technician (MCDT)

ASP.NET MVC

C#

Community College of Rhode Island Lincoln RI Associates in Arts Degree

Employment History

Freelance Web Developer Providence RI Area 02/2019-present

Full-stack, Front & Back End, UI / UX

Advanced Support Center Engineer I Cox Communications, West Warwick RI 01/2013-06/2018

Lead / Trainer (voice, data, video, networking), tester new deployments, procedure development,

Directly work with architect, design, and sales engineers

Applications Specialist – III Lead/Trainer Up-Source, New Bedford MA 01/2012-12/2012

Supporting 3rd party software & hardware applications: troubleshooting, break fix, install.

Consultant/Tech TMC, Cranston RI 11/2010-01/2012

Advice and expertise: networks, web design & development, management, structure and strategy, marketing, build-outs.

CEO Mitchell Construction Inc, Cumberland RI 04/2004-11/2010

Design and development with customers, project management, leadership, sales, consulting, marketing strategies.